(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T21:07:08.899989",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
前略、電子の海は今日も
Dear, the digital sea is today as well
晴れ、時々雪、ところによりパフェ
Sunny, occasionally snowy, parfaits in places
前人未踏のテラバイ島で
On the uncharted Terabyte Island
またどこかのあなたを 待機中
Waiting for you somewhere once again
偶然だって必然のうちは
Even if it's coincidence, while it's destiny
送受信は見えない糸でしょ
Transmission and reception are invisible threads, right?
断然こっちがしっくりくる
This definitely feels much more right
enter×space で escape
Escape with enter x space
the boooom！ここは0と1の楽園
The boooom! Here is a paradise of 0 and 1
the boooom！広く深い世界から見つけだして
The boooom! Find me from this vast and deep world
エレクトリカ・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrica Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here
好みも狂いもいただきます
I'll take your preferences and madness too
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin' Surfin'
手と手と取ってて
Taking hand in hand
白昼夢中 夢中で踊り明かしましょう
Daydreaming, let's dance the night away in a trance
攻略！電子の海は今日も
Strategy! The digital sea is today as well
赤、青、緑ととにかくいっぱいっぱい
Red, blue, green, piled high and full
悠々自適のテラバイ島で
On the leisurely Terabyte Island
待ちかねのいつもの ＝開始中＝
Long-awaited, our usual = Starting now =
そんなそんなそんなそんなあんなようなこと下らなさこそが至福の時でしょ
Such ridiculous things are the ultimate bliss, right?
のんびり で ごー だい あー だ こー だ で いこう
Leisurely, let's go on like this
command×delete で respawn
Respawn with command x delete
the boooom！ここは雲の向こうの未来
The boooom! Here is the future beyond the clouds
the boooom！狭く暗いブラウザじゃ物足りないの
The boooom! A narrow, dark browser just isn't enough
エレクトリカ・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrica Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here
酸いも甘いも忘れてさ
Forgetting both the sweet and sour
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin' Surfin'
手と手と取ってて
Taking hand in hand
白昼夢中 夢中にするわ 覚えていてね
Daydreaming, I'll captivate you, remember that
ユーロビートの風
The wind of Eurobeat
聞こえてきて何じゃこりゃ
I hear it coming, what on earth is this?
無物質な水平線 スレッガー悠々 もう一回
Immaterial horizon, Sleggar leisurely, once more
まだためがい なんて
Still hesitant, saying things like
この指にとまれ 追加ボーナス頂戴 まだまだ足りない
Perch on this finger, give me extra bonus, still not enough
で、そうえすのーと もういいかい もう待てない 今すぐ会って
So, SOS note, ready or not, can't wait anymore, meet me right now
エレクトリカ・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrica Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here
世界線を飛び出しちゃって
Jumping right across worldlines
君のトポロジー感じたいんだ
I want to feel your topology
意識が乱れて ディスプレイを飛び出させて
Consciousness gets scrambled, making me leap out of the display
秘密ゼロの心ウラから共鳴して
Resonate from the bottom of a zero-secret heart
夢見てこう 飛び行く音は
Let's dream on, the soaring sound is
ピコピコ音は よ
Piko-piko sound is, yeah
ベテランなこの感情 アナログに変化して
This veteran emotion transforming into analog
キロキロわーいらく 最高は一秒止められない
Kilo-kilo joyful paradise, the peak cannot be stopped for even a second
この招待 賛成 鳴らしの会館 土砂降りも台風も 出歩きたくないよってでばそう
This invitation, approval, ringing hall, heavy rain and typhoons too, saying I don't want to go out, let's step out
エレクトリカ・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrica Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here
この声を 感じるんだ
Feeling this voice
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin' Surfin'
手と手と取ってて
Taking hand in hand
不条風を飛び出しちゃって 君に出会いを届けるんだ
Jumping out against unreasonable winds, delivering encounters to you
セーブが壊れちゃって プログラムが溢れちゃって
Save data broken, programs overflowing
きっと笑い合えるね
We'll definitely be able to smile together
夢見てこう
Let's dream on
この声を 届けよ
Deliver this voice
夢見ごこち
Dreamlike state
ピコピコ音は よ
Piko-piko sound is, yeah
夜のトバりが降りたらね
When night's veil falls once more,
またやってくるの
it will come again.
月と太陽のおしゃべり 愛しいキミの胸の中
The chatter of the moon and sun, deep within your cherished heart.
ただ眠りたいの それだけなのに
I just want to sleep, yet even so...
同じお空で繋がってる
Connected under the same sky...
切ないの 黄昏 水面が揺らいだら
It's painful at dusk, when the water's surface ripples.
あなたの声でとかして欲しい
I want you to melt it away with your voice.
こんな夜をそっと届けたい
I want to gently deliver a night like this.
叶えてマイラバーズリーナ 静かな寝息を下さい
Grant my wish, my lover's rina, give me quiet breathing.
ここに一冊の絵本があります
Here is a picture book.
とても古い絵本です
It is a very old picture book.
その本が描かれたのは この星からずっとずっと離れた 銀河をゆく船の中
That book was drawn inside a ship traveling through the galaxy, far, far away from this star.
永い時をかけて 星から星へと旅する船です
It is a ship that spends endless time traveling from star to star.
この本は 船に暮らす子供たちのために描かれました
This book was drawn for the children living on the ship.
くら～い ばしょを 女の子が歩いてる
A girl is walking through a dark place.
目の前には どこまでも続く白い道
Before her is a white road continuing endlessly.
いつから歩いているか わからないけど 元気に歩く
She doesn't know how long she's been walking, but she walks cheerfully.
「この道は光っていてきれいだな」「それにとっても歩きやすい！」
"This road is shining and so pretty!" "And it's very easy to walk on!"
女の子は歩くのが好きみたい 元気よく てくてく歩いていく
The girl seems to like walking, walking along cheerfully step by step.
「あっ 流れ星！」「きれいなお星さま！」
"Ah, a shooting star!" "What a pretty star!"
「熱くはないみたい さわってみよう」
"It doesn't seem hot. Let's touch it."
「光っていてすてきなお星も」「お星さまのぞいてみよう！」
"A glowing, wonderful star too." "Let's peek into the star!"
「まあ みたことない世界！」
"Oh, a world I've never seen before!"
女の子は落ちてくる星を通して 色々な世界を覗きます
Through the falling stars, the girl peeks into various worlds.
この絵本はとても古いものです
This picture book is very old.
なので 最後のページがなくなってしまっています
Therefore, the final page is missing.
船の中にいる大人も子供も考えました
Both the adults and children on the ship thought about it.
結末がわからないのは残念だけど
It's a shame not knowing the ending, but...
続きのお話を考えるのは 少し楽しいことでした
thinking about the continuation of the story was a little fun.
この本のタイトルは……
The title of this book is...
ときのおそら 5th Anniversary Live 宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ
[Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live: Milky Way of Space and Spacetime]
恋する私 がんばる
I'm trying my best as a girl in love,
ほらね？ キラキラキラ 煌めいている
see? Sparkling and shining brightly.
太陽みたいに 笑う私の
My smile like the sun
メマメマメマぐるしい ラブストーリー
is a dizzying love story.
ああ もう！ やんなっちゃうわ
Ah, geez! It's so frustrating,
今度ばかりは 許せないの！
I won't forgive you this time!
その悪気なさげな 君の笑顔が
That innocent-looking smile of yours
大嫌いが いつからか 大好きになった
went from something I hated to something I love.
…今日のところは 許してあげるわ
...I'll forgive you for today, so hey,
だからほら早く 君から答え聞かせて？
hurry up and give me your answer!
さっき泣き虫の君のエラーが
Your crying errors from a moment ago
だいだいだいだいだい嫌いが
My absolute, total hatred
いつの間にか大好きになった
Somehow turned into deep affection
今日のところは許してあげるわ
I'll forgive you just for today
だから
So
ほら早く君から答え聞かせて
Come on, hurry and let me hear your answer
いつまでも反論を
Giving me endless rebuttals
もう目を逸らさないでよ
Don't look away from me anymore
こここここーいする
Fall, fall, fall in love
私が必ずいつも君君君を捕まえてる
I'm always definitely catching you, you, you
たたた太陽みたいに笑うその顔がおが大好きなんです
Your smile like the sun is what I love so much
こここここーいする
Fall, fall, fall in love
私が輝くほらにきらきらきらめいてる
I am sparkling brightly at you who shines
たたた太陽みたいに笑う私と君の目まめまぐるしいラブストーリー
A dizzying love story between you and me
ずっと気になってた
I've been wondering about you all along
君にふさわしいのは誰
Who is worthy of you?
今がない私自身とかないから
Because I don't even have myself right now
くるぐるぐるぐる駆け巡る
Whirling and spinning around
プラスマイナス思考回路
A plus-minus thought circuit
今日のところはひと休みするわ
I'll take a break for today
でもね本音だよ二人見てきた景色って更新へと変わる
The scenery the two of us have seen is changing
もう手を離さないわ
I won't let go of your hand anymore
こここここーいする
Fall, fall, fall in love
私が覚えるいつも君君君を思ってから
Always thinking of you, you, you
たたたいたんふたになれるどうしてそんなだって言わせないで
Don't make me say why it has to be like that
こここここーいする私が輝くほらにきらきらきらめいてる
Fall, fall, fall in love, sparkling brightly
たたた単純見つめていてまだまだソワソワ終われないラブストーリー
A simple gaze, still restless, a love story
みんな盛り上がってね今日は声が出せないけどクラップ＆ペンライトで盛り上がってねコメントまでもよ！
Get hyped with claps and penlights, and in the comments too!
ふたりつばさはないけれど繋いだ両手で無敵なのよ
We don't have wings, but joined hands make us invincible
疑う余地もないわ期待しててね
There's no room for doubt, so look forward to it
こここここーいする私と決めるずっと君君君と探していく
Fall in love, deciding with me, searching for you
たたたた大好きそんな気持ちを100年100年に積まれても
So much love, even if accumulated over 100 years
こここここーいする私が輝くほらにきらきらきらめいてる
Fall in love, sparkling brightly at you
たたた単純見つめていて私と君の目まめまぐるしいいつでももぐるぐる忙しいラブストーリー
A simple gaze, a dizzying, busy love story
まーるい空
A round sky
胸に詰め込んだ夢はぐしゃぐしゃで
The dreams packed into my chest are all crumpled up
勇気はいるけど君にだけは見せようかな
It takes courage, but maybe I'll show only you
一緒にいけるかな君のぼっちを渡してこう
Can we go together? Let's hand over your loneliness
深呼吸をしてわかったこと存在で
Taking a deep breath, realizing our existence
そしてはっきりとした存在で
And a clear presence
笑っちゃうくらい最高な夢を
A dream so wonderful it makes you laugh
いつでも行かないよ譲れぬ今日に歌って
Singing into a day we cannot yield
最高の教科書に二度と戻したらなんだってやれそうだ
If we could return to the best textbook, we could do anything
落書きの中で光ってたものを
The things that shone within the graffiti
君として交し合えたなって
Exchanging them with you
望みたいならもっとわかり合えないよね
If you want to hope for more, we can't understand each other
次も甘いもの集めたのをしようとな
Gathering sweet things next time too
成長できるかなともに歩みも
Can we grow? Walking together
見つけ合おうダンスダンスー上の川の中
Finding each other within the river above
恋する 私 かがやく
Falling in love, I shine.
ほらね？ キラキラキラ 煌めいている
See? Sparkling, shining brightly.
太陽 みたいに 笑う 私の
Smiling like the sun, my
めまぐるしい ラブストーリー
dizzying love story.
昨日よりも 加速してる
Accelerating even more than yesterday,
ちゃんと繋いでて
hold my hand tightly.
簡単じゃない ホームの 呼び声は
The calls from the home aren't simple,
いつも キミが 明るく放って 支えてくれる ずっと
You always brightly call out and support me.
刻まれてくんだよ
It's being carved into my heart.
みんなが 見守ってくれて ありがとう
Thank you everyone for watching over me!
二階席！
Second-floor seats!
コメント！
Comments!
上手くいかないよなんて
Saying things like "It's not going well,"
弱音吐いた パスの教科書 水に溶いたら
if I dissolve that textbook of complaints in water,
なんてって やれそうな ワクワクの中 引っ掛けた 思いを
the feelings caught up in that exciting thought.
キミとして 足並み揃えようなんて
Walking in step with you,
嘘みたいだな もっと
it feels like a lie, even more.
温かいてしるして
Leave a warm mark.
はい、ということで
Yes, so,
最初から ぐるぐるラブストーリー ロゴマッチと お待たせしちゃいました！
sorry to keep you waiting after starting with "Guruguru Love Story"!
改めまして ときのそらのーー！
Once again, it's Tokino Sora's—!
みんな見に来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you everyone for coming to see me!
すごい、その人がいっぱいいる、当たり前なんだけど、コメントも見えてるよ。ありがとう！
Amazing, there are so many people—well, obviously, but I can see your comments too. Thank you!
二階席の人ーー！ありがとうーー！
Second-floor seats! Thank you!
一階席の、みんなーー！ありがとうーー！
First-floor seats, everyone! Thank you!
コメントーー！
Comments!
本日はときのそら5周年記念ライブ「そらとときのミルキーウェイ」昼公演にお越しいただきありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending the daytime performance of Tokino Sora's 5th Anniversary Live "Sora to Toki no Milky Way" today.
今日はね、今年1月に開催したシアターカルバライブロールプレイに続いて、昼と夜のニコをやっていこうと思っています。
Today, following the Theater Trickal Cover Live Roleplay held in January this year, we're planning to do the daytime and nighttime niko.
私、ときのそらはね、今年5周年を迎えて、
I, Tokino Sora, am celebrating my 5th anniversary this year,
あの、ありがとう！ありがとう！
um, thank you! Thank you!
見えてるよ、パチパチ見えてるよ。みんなナイトも守ってくれてありがとう。持ってない人もパチパチありがとうございます。
I can see you, I can see you clapping. Thank you everyone for keeping the night too. And thank you to those who don't have one as well.
なんか、もう5年経ったんだっていうすごい不思議な感覚があるんですけども、まあね、5周年にふさわしいようにすごい頑張ってきました。
I have this strange feeling that 5 years have already passed, but anyway, I've worked really hard to be worthy of the 5th anniversary.
スペシャルで、なんだろう、とてもなんか輝かしいというか、ミラクルなミラクルなライブになっていると思うので、最後までね、
It's special, I don't know, very brilliant, kind of a miraculous, miraculous live performance, so right until the end,
なんかこう、目一杯、パッと開いて、全力で楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you could open your eyes wide and enjoy it with all your might!
右の人！
People on the right!
左の人！
People on the left!
今日はね、今生の楽器が聞こえてると思うんですけど、こんな素敵な演奏をしてくださる皆さんとも一緒に楽しんでいきたいなと思ってるんですよ。バンドの皆さん！
Today, I think you can hear live instruments, and I want to enjoy this together with everyone who plays such wonderful music. Band members!
今日はね、ソラバンドがいるんですよね。
Today, we have the Sora Band here.
そして、これからも本のひととかスターリングスの皆さんも出てきてくださいますのでお楽しみに。よろしくお願いします。
And from now on, people from Hon and Starings will also be appearing, so look forward to it. Thank you very much.
みんな、二曲、まだ二曲だけど、盛り上がれてる？盛り上がってるね、ありがとう。ちゃんと見えてるよ。
Everyone, two songs in, it's only two songs, but are you getting hyped? You're hyped, thank you. I can see you clearly.
で、うちわ持ってくれてる人、ぬいぐるみ持ってくれてる人、めちゃくちゃお洒落してくれてる人、ちゃんと見えてるよ。ありがとう。二階席のみんなももちろん見えてるからね！
And the people holding uchiwa fans, holding plushies, dressed up so fashionably—I can see you clearly. Thank you. Of course I can see everyone in the second-floor seats too!
みんな楽しみにしてくれてるよね。
You're all looking forward to it, right?
既にね、発表されているんですけど
It's already been announced, but
今回のスペシャルなゲスト、いらっしゃいます！
we have a special guest today!
会場のみんなには、心のね中から、まあうわあって心、心で出してね。
Everyone in the venue, from the bottom of your hearts... well, \"whoa\", express it in your hearts.
あの声、実際出したらちょっと大変なことになっちゃうから、あの、と拍手で！
Um, if you actually use your voices, it'll get a bit crazy, so um, with applause!
配信のみんなは「イエーイ」とか「うおー」とか「やったー」とか、
Everyone watching the stream, \"Yay\", \"Whoa\", \"Yay!\", and all that.
あ、でもいいよ、なんだかいろんなコメントで盛り上げてくれたら嬉しいと思います。
Ah, either way is fine, I'd be happy if you hype it up with all sorts of comments.
さあ、誰だと思いすか？
Now, who do you think it is?
コメントの人掛けれるかな？
Can the chat people guess?
せーので言ってみよう。せーの！ 日野下こうみさん！
Let's all say it together. Ready, go! Hinoshita Koumi-san!
そうなんですよ。今日はね、ゲストに大々、大先輩の日野下こうみさんをお迎えして
That's right. Today, welcoming our mega senior guest, Hinoshita Koumi-san,
ね、来てくれるなんて奇跡じゃない？すごいよね。
right, for her to come is a miracle, isn't it? That's amazing.
ね、こんなふうにね、なんかアーティストの大先輩の人とのコラボさせていただくのって、初めてだとうんだよね。自分のライブではもちろん初めてで。
Right, collaborating with a senior artist like this, I think it's the very first time. In my own concert, of course, it's the first.
前にもね、YouTubeにもね、あの、出演させていただいたりしたんだけど
Before too, on YouTube, um, I got to appear on her channel or she on mine,
もう、ドキ緊張で、もうカチカチで、なんか、私がもしそうなってたらみんな、うおーって緊張しないで盛り上がれよみたいな感じのこう、あ、そうね、やってくれたら嬉しいです。
but I was super nervous, stiff as a board, thinking \"If I act like that, everyone go 'Whoa', don't be nervous, get hyped!\", so um, yeah, I'd be happy if you do that.
いやあ、しっかりと驚きだけできるように頑張りますね。
Well then, I'll do my best to surprise everyone properly.
みんな、ついてきてくれるよね？ついてきてくれるよね？ついてきてくれるよね？ありがとう！
Everyone, you'll follow along with me, right? You'll follow along, right? You'll follow along, right? Thank you!
さてさて、おしゃべりしてばかりもね、良くないでしょ、ライブですから。
Now, now, just chatting away isn't good either, since this is a live concert.
というわけで、この後もがっつり楽しんでいきましょう。
So, let's thoroughly enjoy the rest of this too.
それでは聞いてください。
Now then, please listen.
「カラノソラ」
"Karano Sora"
まだです。
Not yet.
あ、そうだ。皆さん、あと1曲言い忘れておりました。なんと、YouTubeの無料配信はこの後の曲の途中までということになっています。YouTubeで楽しんでいる皆さんは、スポン生のサイトから続きがご覧になれますので、ぜひせっかくここまで見てくれたからこの後もついてきてほしいななんて思います！
Ah, that's right. Everyone, there's one song I forgot to mention. As it turns out, the free YouTube stream will run until the middle of the next song. Those enjoying on YouTube can watch the rest from the SPWN site, so I really hope you'll stick with us through the rest since you've come this far!
いやあ、緊張しちゃって、言いたいこと忘れちゃったよ。
Man, I got so nervous, I forgot what I wanted to say.
それでは次の曲いきますかね。今初めて聞いたみたいな反応して。
Well then, shall we go to the next song? Act like you're hearing it for the first time.
それでは聞いてください。「カラノソラ」
Now then, please listen. "Karano Sora".
奇跡のような
Like a miracle,
キミと作るメモリー
memories made with you.
ギュッと握り締め 願ったよ
I held on tight and wished.
きっと開花する ワクワクの新芽
Surely blooming, exciting new buds.
この場所が初めての 紡ぐ道標
This place is our first spun guidepost.
ちょっとづつでも 踏み入れてみて
Take a step into it, little by little.
幸せはすぐ傍にあるものだから 恐がらないで 夢中になる その力を... For you
Happiness is right by your side, so don't be afraid, lose yourself in that power... For you
この空に花咲かせてみせるよ
I'll make flowers bloom in this sky.
何よりも強い 生命の息
The breath of life, stronger than anything.
涙は未来の味方になるから 隣で拭いてあげる
Tears will become the future's ally, so I'll wipe them away by your side.
小さな幸せが積もる未来へ
Toward a future where small happiness piles up.
La la... 口ずさむ安らぎは
La la... The humming peace
足跡が語る 証の結晶
Is a crystal of proof spoken by our footprints.
次はキミが居るから 希望は無限だね
Next you'll be there, so hope is infinite.
一歩づつから始めてみるよ 一緒に過ごして宝物より尊い 夢の続きを 叶えて行こう 伝えて行こう... With you
I'll start taking it one step at a time, spending time together more precious than treasure, let's fulfill the continuation of our dreams, let's convey it... With you
ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live 宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ
[Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live: Milky Way of Space and Spacetime]
無料視聴パートはここまでとなります 全編ご視聴したい方は概要欄をご確認ください
This is the end of the free viewing part. Please check the description to watch the full version.
ときのそら 5th Anniversary Live 宇宙と時空のミルキーウェイ
Tokino Sora 5th Anniversary Live: Space and Spacetime Milky Way
無料視聴パートはここまでとなります 全編ご視聴したい方は概要欄をご確認ください
This concludes the free preview. Please check the description to watch the full version.